Roberto Andrés Alvarado Moreira

Motivated student and programmer dedicated to the study of mathematics and its applications within computer science and web development, also passionate about the new technologies, artificial intelligence, optimization methods and numerical analysis. Searching opportunities to learn and delve deeper into the world of new technological research

□ raalvaradom@hotmail.com
 □ (+593)988718378

https://github.com/Robdres

Quito, Ecuador

Tools

Languages

Spanish • • • • • • English

Programming Languages \square

Python
MySQL
JavaScript
Java
Latex
C++
Rust

Developer Tools

Vim
Git
Figma
VSCode

Platforms

Linux Oocker Ookons

Frameworks y Libraries

Angular
TensorFlow
NodeJs

Skills

Leadership
Critical Thinking
Teamwork
Communication

Certificates

Huawei Technologies, Seed for the Future, Leadership in Engineering Bootcamp

October,2022

Professional Experience

Junior Programmer

January,2022-Febraury 2023

Tecsicom

Quito, Ecuador

With a small group of programmers we were able to create a complete Angular based website for the daily operations of one of the biggest marketing companies in Ecuador

Researcher

June,2021-Present

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Along with all my teammates in the artificial intelligence laboratory in the university, we have used neural networks to learn and create new applications for Al in our environment

Data Analysist

May,2023-Present

Ney Torres Investment Fund

Quito, Ecuador

In charge to analyse and work with financial datasets to assess and improve stock trading analysis

Teaching Assistant

June,2022-March,2023

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

I have helped and collaborated with David Hervas, Math PhD, with academic activities

Education

Math Major

January,2019-May,2023

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Courses: Numerical Analysis, Neural Networks, Differential Geometry, Real Analysis, Stochastic Processes

Computer Science Major

January,2020-May,2024

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Courses: Artificial Intelligence, Databases, Computer Architecture, Java Programming, C++ Programming

Philosophy Minor

January,2018-May,2024

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Courses: Philosophy of Religion, History of philosophy , Process Philosophy, Platonic Dialogues

Projects

Neural Networks

June,2022-Present

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Quito, Ecuador

Work inside many computer vision projects, many of them them guided by me. Learning and creating usefull applications of AI inside our world

Testors

August,2021-Present

Universidad San Francisco de Quito

Learn and participate in many projects that involve the use of testors, also known as rough sets, in order to reach better processing times by reducing the number of attributes necessary for classification processes

Palm Tree

January,2023-May,2023

Quito, Ecuador

Alongside professor Miguel Castillo from NC State University, it was possible to work with a database of the Palm Tree, to create metrics to analyse the performance of difference infrared measure devices.

Computer Vision

January,2023-Present

Quito, Ecuador

Alongside professor Julio Ibarra from USFQ, the computer vision project will try to reconstruct a face based on a photograph